(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-25T21:01:17.088641",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
扉を開けたら
When I open the door,
新しい世界へ
to a brand new world,
飛び出そうよ
let's leap right in!
キミと一緒なら
As long as I'm with you,
どこへだって行ける
we can go anywhere.
高鳴る胸の鼓動
The beating of my pounding heart
リズムに合わせて
matches the rhythm,
一歩ずつ踏み出そう
taking it one step at a time.
きらめく星空へと
Toward the glittering starry sky,
Step Into Dreams!
何気ない日常も
Even our ordinary days
キミといるだけで
just by being with you
特別な宝物
turn into special treasures.
笑い合えるこの瞬間
This moment of sharing smiles
ずっと続きますように
I hope will last forever.
どんな壁があっても
No matter what walls stand in our way,
乗り越えられるから
we can overcome them,
信じる力を胸に
with the power of belief in our hearts,
未来へと手を伸ばそう
let's reach out toward the future.
きらめく星空へと
Toward the glittering starry sky,
飛び立とう、今すぐに
let's take flight, right now!
キミと描くストーリー
The story we paint together,
Step Into Dreams!
迷いそうな時でも
Even when I feel lost,
キミの声が聞こえる
I can hear your voice
「大丈夫だよ」って
saying, "It's going to be okay."
背中を押してくれる
Pushing me forward.
だから私は進める
That's why I can keep moving forward
どんな遠くへだって
no matter how far away.
この想いを乗せて
Carrying these feelings with me,
翼を広げて
spreading my wings
もっと高くへ
even higher,
さあ、行こう！
now, let's go!
扉を開けたら
When I open the door,
新しい世界へ
to a brand new world,
飛び出そうよ
let's leap right in!
キミと一緒なら
As long as I'm with you,
どこへだって行ける
we can go anywhere.
きらめく星空へと
Toward the glittering starry sky,
Step Into Dreams!
みんな、ありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
またね！
See you!
ああ、いつものように
Ah, like every day,
過ぎる日々にあくびが出る
yawning through passing days.
さざめく夜、越え、今日も
Crossing the noisy night, again today,
渋谷の街に朝が降る
morning falls on the streets of Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような そんな気持ち
Feeling somewhat empty inside,
つまらないな でもそれでいい
how boring, but I suppose that's fine.
そんなもんさ これでいい
That's just how it is, this is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた本当の声を響かせてよ ほら
Let your hidden true voice resonate, come on!
見ないふりをしていても確かにそこにある
Even if you turn a blind eye, it's definitely there.
感じたままに描く
Painting just as I felt,
自分で選んだその色で
in the colors I chose for myself.
眠い空気纏う朝に訪れた青い世界
In the morning wrapped in sleepy air, a blue world arrived.
好きなものを好きだと言う
Saying that I love what I love,
怖くて仕方ないけど
even though it's terrifying,
本当の自分に出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I finally met my true self.
手を伸ばせば 伸ばすほどに
The more I reach out my hands,
遠くへ行く
the further away they go.
思うようにいかない 今日もまた慌ただしくもがいている
Nothing goes as planned, struggling frantically once again today.
悔しい気持ちも ただ情けなくて
Frustrated feelings, feeling so helpless,
涙が出る 踏み込むほど苦しくなる 痛くもなる
tears fall; the deeper I step, the more painful and agonizing it gets.
感じたままに進む
Moving forward just as I felt,
自分で選んだこの道を
down this path I chose myself.
重いまぶた擦る夜にしがみついた青い誓い
Clinging to a blue vow on a night rubbing heavy eyelids,
好きなことを続けることは それは「楽しい」だけじゃない
continuing what you love isn't just "fun."
本当にできる? 不安になるけど
Can I really do it? Though it makes me uneasy,
ああ なんまいでも ほら なんまいでも
Ah, no matter how many times, see, no matter how many times,
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
I've kept drawing because I lacked confidence.
Let it all out,
強がらなくていいんだね
You don't have to pretend to be tough.
誰かが描いてってた壁の落書きの花が揺れる
The graffiti flower on the wall that someone drew is trembling.
自分らしさなんて誰もわからないよ
No one knows what makes them unique.
長い長い道の途中で失くしたり拾ったり
As you travel this long, long road you'll lose some things and pick some up,
急に寂しくなって泣いちゃう日もあるけど
though there'll be days when you suddenly feel lonely and just want to cry.
涙も痛みも星に変えよう
We'll turn all the tears and all the pain into stars,
明を照らす灯をともそう
We'll light the light that brightens our tomorrow.
小さく迷ってもふたりで作ろう星屑を
Even if we get a little lost, together we'll make stardust,
強く光る永遠を探そう
We'll search for the forever that shines powerfully.
Let it all out, Let it all out,
足りないことだらけだよね
There's a lot of things you lack, aren't there?
足りなくていいんだね だから君と出会えたんだ
That's how I met you in the first place.
「確か」が何なのかそれが知りたくて
You wanted to know exactly what tomorrow was,
小さなナイフを靴下の中に隠してた
You had a little knife hidden in your sock.
強がってついた嘘の方がずっと痛かった
Putting on a brave face and telling the lie hurt so much more.
本当は怖いよ だけど生きてく
In reality you're scared, but you keep on living.
笑顔の君を風が撫でてく
The meaning behind your smile is playing in the wind.
小さな手かざしてふたりで作ろう
Let's hold up our hands and together make stardust,
星屑を 強く光る永遠を探そう
We'll search for the forever that shines powerfully.
正しいことが間違ってたらどうすればいい?
What should we do if what we thought was right turns out to be wrong?
悲しいことが正しかったら受け入れるだけ?
We can only accept that some truths will cause us sorrow.
失くしたと思ってた でも君が知ってた
I thought I had lost it, but you knew all along.
君がいて本当によかった
I'm so thankful you were there.
Stepping out to the world
Where all the lights are gone
眠れない 眠れない
I can't sleep, I can't sleep
When all the bustle is gone
When all the grouch is done
逃げ出せ 逃げ出せ Run away, run away, run away
Run away, run away, run away
So I just stepped out of the window on a silent road.
静まり返る住宅の地
The residential area is quiet and still.
霧雨タタタタ淡々と アスファルト リズムパターン刻んでる
Drizzle steadily beating a rhythm on the asphalt.
息を吐いて吸ってもう一手って 前へ前へって
Breathe in, breathe out, one more step, forward, and forward.
自覚のないままに 酸素が染み渡ってきて
Without even realizing it, oxygen permeates through.
赤い血が巡り巡って 言葉になって
Red blood circulates and turns into words.
喉カラカラ潤して
With a dry, parched throat,
タララララ「僕等」は 中途半端な満足で 事足りるようになっていった 過去を悔やむ
we became satisfied with mediocre contentment, regretting the past.
霧雨やんで 電信柱が光って 小さな水はね
The drizzle stops, utility poles shine, little water splashes.
僕はタラララと 掠れた鼻歌唄いながら ペースを上げた
I hummed a raspy tune like tararara and picked up the pace.
毒を吐いて吸ってもう一手って 前へ前へって
Spit out the poison, inhale, one more step, forward, and forward.
自覚のないままに「僕等」の中に群れたれ
Without realizing it, gathered among us,
白い息巡り巡って 旋律になって 命からがら走った
White breath circulates, turns into a melody, and we ran for our lives.
のらりくらりと「僕」は 逸れる事を選んだんだ
Aimlessly, I chose to stray away.
本当に満たしてくれる物探すため
To search for something that truly fulfills me.
高望みと言われて 才能が無いと言われても
Even if called ambitious, even if told I have no talent,
怯える程僕は賢くなくて
I'm not wise enough to be intimidated.
1番になったって 2番になったって
Whether I become number one, or number two,
結局最後は 皆消えてくんだ
in the end, everyone disappears.
僕が死んだって 何も残らないから
Even if I die, nothing will be left behind,
生きているそのうちは 死んでたまるか
While I'm still alive, there's no way I'll die.
のらりくらりと「僕」は これから先も生意気で
Aimlessly, I will continue to be sassy from now on,
大声で歌って笑って たまに泣いて
Singing out loud, laughing, and occasionally crying.
タララララ「僕等」は 中途半端な満足じゃ 事足りぬようになって 現在に至る
We could no longer make do with mediocre contentment, leading to the present.
Run away, run away, run away
ペンライトの準備は足りてる?
So, are your penlights ready?
ホライブのいろいろ全念タント、水宮枢でーす!
Live-Glow's multi-colored centan-tots, is Mizumiya Su-desu!
ということで、「Step into Dreamers」始まりました! イエーイ!
And with that, Step into Dreamers has started! Yay!
今回はですね、オープニングにもあった通り、夢だったホロライブに入って、夢だった初のソロ…
This time, as was in the opening, it was a solo concert entering Hololive's dream!
えーたんライブ3D イェーイ！
E-tan Live 3D, yay!
ちょっとめちゃめちゃに緊張しているんですけれども、
I'm feeling super, super nervous right now, but...
どうだった？郡道お嬢とアイスアウト、コメント欄どうだった？かっこよかった？
how was it? Gundo-ojou and Ice Out, how was it in the comments? Was it cool?
かっこよかったってきっと、まあ、この後流れるんだろうな。かっこよかっただろ？(笑)
"It was cool," so I'm sure that'll play right after. It was cool, right? Haha!
いっぱい褒めてください。
Please shower me with praise!
今回はですね、タイトルにもある通り、もうステップがもう、めちゃめちゃに、もうステップがステップもう、めちゃめちゃに多かったりですね、
This time, as the title suggests, there were so, so many steps...
あとはやったことのないジャンルのダンスにも挑戦しちゃったりしていますので、お楽しみに！
And I also challenged myself with genres of dance I've never done before, so look forward to it!
ハッシュタグは、こちらにあるハッシュタグ水宮生誕祭2026です！
The hashtag is #MizumiyaBirthday2026 right here!
スクショとか感想とかたくさんポストしてくれてると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you post lots of screenshots and thoughts!
目指せトレンド！みんないっぱいポストしてね！
Aim for trending! Everyone, post lots, okay?
このあとはですね、ゲストパートにも行きたいと思っているのですが、
After this, I'd like to move on to the guest part, but...
なんと お祝いの映像が届いてるみたいなので、見てみましょう！こっちかな？
it seems a congratulatory video has arrived, so let's go check it out! This way?
よし！
Alright!
なんだなんだ？
What, what is this?
君の笑顔をご案内、ナンフーの観光大使で23時所属、文筆家野成功、しがりこだよ！
Guiding you with a smile, Nanfu's tourism ambassador, affiliated with 23:00, writer of success, Shigariko here!
りこだよ！
Riko here!
水宮、お誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう！
Mizumiya, happy birthday! Thank you!
期待いま、水宮は最高のライブをしていることでしょう。
Right about now, Mizumiya is probably putting on the best live performance.
そっか、おめでとう！ありがとう！
Is that so? Happy birthday! Thank you!
本当はね、現地で直接お祝いがしたかったんですけど、どうしてもスケジュールが合わないということで、
Honestly, I wanted to celebrate in person at the venue, but our schedules just wouldn't align,
ちょっとお祝いのメッセージ動画をね、今回送らせていただいております。
so I've sent this congratulatory message video instead.
水宮とはね、泥沼としてもうたくさんコラボして、プライベートとかでもテーマパーク行ったりとか、映画行ったりとかも、月1でお泊まりするくらいの…！
Mizumiya and I, as "doronuma", have collaborated so much, gone to theme parks privately, gone to movies, and even sleep over about once a month...!
ちょっと仲良くね、させてもらってても本当にいつもありがとう！事務所がね、違うのにもうこんなに仲良くなれるなんて
Thanks for always being so close with me! Even though our agencies are different, being able to get this close...
もうめちゃめちゃ嬉しいし、いつも水宮に元気もらって支えてもらってます。
I'm just so happy, and Mizumiya always gives me energy and supports me.
これからもずっと友達！いっぱい遊んでいっぱい楽しいことしていこうね！大好きだよ！
Friends forever from now on! Let's hang out a lot and do lots of fun things! Love you!
それでは、しがりこでした！この後もライブ楽しんでね！頑張れ！ありがとう！
Well then, that was Shigariko! Enjoy the rest of the live too! Do your best! Thank you!
うわはははは！
Wahahaha!
ということで、しがりこからメッセージが来ました！ありがとうしがりこ！こっちにいるかな？ありがとうしがりこー！
And with that, a message came from Shigariko! Thank you, Shigariko! Is she over here? Thank you, Shigariko!
いやそう、今回はね、ちょっとスケジュールが合わなくて、ちょっとりこの3Dにはね、ちょっと呼んでもらって一緒に入ったんですけど、
Yeah, so this time, our schedules didn't quite match up, and though she invited me to Riko's 3D and we performed together,
ちょっとすうのライブでは今回は踊れなかったけど、いつか一緒にまた踊ろうな！ありがとうねりこ、水宮頑張れよ！
I couldn't dance at Su's live this time, but let's dance together again someday! Thanks, Riko, do your best, Mizumiya!
応援してもらったし、ちょっと次の曲に行こうかな？ちょっと次はゲストパートだから誰が来るのかな？
Since she cheered me on, shall we move on to the next song? Next is the guest part, so who could it be?
このあともまだまだ続きます！そしてなんか告知もあるかもしれないので最後まで楽しんでねー！
This will still keep going after this! And there might be some announcements too, so enjoy until the very end!
おこちゃま戦争 作詞：れをる 作曲：ギガ
Okochama Sensou (Childish War)
Lyrics: Reol, Music: Giga
昔々のそのまた昔 とある貴族の仲良しな兄弟
Long, long ago, even further back,
a pair of close noble siblings
（以下略称）
(Abbreviated below)
「ちゃんときれ！」
"Do it properly!"
じいやが呼ぶ 席につけ よーいどん！
The butler calls, take your seats,
ready, go!
ナイフとフォークで応戦いたしますの
We retaliate with knife and fork
だって僕らはブルジョアの 立派な立派な貴族様なんですのよ
Because we are bourgeois,
proper, proper noble lords, you see
ひでりふせぐみ無き君との違いを ヴァイヴァイスロイ見せてやるぜ
Showing you the difference between us, trivial subjects—
Viceroy, I'll show you!
おい まてまて また勝手にそんな 見くびるようなハッタリかまして
Hey, wait, wait, acting on your own again
with such looking-down bluffs
はーい はーい はーい はーい お兄様の仰せのままに(笑)
Yes, yes, yes, yes,
as big brother commands (haha)
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, it pisses me off!
Seriously pisses me off!
兄に対して生意気な態度
Such an insolent attitude
toward your older brother
闇の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Voice of the darkness, ring the gong!
ケンカ勃発で宣戦布告
Declare war with the outbreak of a fight
いたずらして 悪ノリして ほらほら煽って行くstyleで
Playing pranks, joining in on the bad mood,
teasingly instigating style
“大安売り”買えちゃったら 毎度ありがとうで君の負け！
If you buy the "bargain sale",
thanks as always, you lose!
（っしゃあ！）
(Hell yeah!)
踊り明かせど煽り合いの駆け引きで決める
Dancing the night away,
decided by provocative bargaining
兄の威厳見せるため飴と鞭 火花散らす チル 両者の目と目
To show brotherly dignity, carrot and stick,
sparks flying, chill, eyes meeting
俺を誰だと思ってるくらい俺様がルールブック
Wondering who I think I am—
I am the rulebook!
へたれじゃない ひよってない ちょっと勇気が足りないだけ
Not playing timid, not flinching,
just lacking a bit of courage
さあさみなさんお手を拝借
Now, everyone, lend me your hands
当たり前だろ 優勝は ガチ勢イ
Obviously, victory goes to
the hardcore fans!
ハイロンパ ハイロンパ ハイロンパ もらってくぜビザイ
Hi-ronpa, hi-ronpa, hi-ronpa,
I'm taking the victory!
はーい はいはいはい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
ほなまる よくできました☆
Good job, gold star!
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
So annoying! Seriously annoying!
僕に向かって 減らす口なんざ
Giving me lip right to my face,
とっておきを きみに見舞え
I'll give you a taste of my best!
報復 制裁 挑発しちゃって
Retaliating, punishing, provoking you—
意地悪して 一枚上
Being mean, staying one step ahead.
チャンスは貰ってくスタンスで
Staking my stance to grab every chance,
痛恨ミス、あっちゃっちゃ
Fatal miss, oops, oh well.
お生憎様だね 君の負け
Too bad for you, you lose!
yes!
だけどキミ キミだけが
But you, only you...
ボクに似合いのライバル
...are the rival suited for me.
オチるのも へこんでんのも
Whether falling or feeling down,
調子狂わせるから
...it throws off my rhythm.
今宵もてめぇと...
Tonight with you again...
だいたい兄様がいつもそうやって nayo nayo してるから
Big brother is always acting so timid,
僕が兄様的分まで積極的にやってやってんだよ
so I take the initiative and do his share too!
もう少し感謝してほしいね
Show a little gratitude, will you?
年上のくせに全然頼りにされないおにい様とかばっかりだよもう
You're older yet completely useless as a big brother!
今日から僕が兄だ これ決定
Starting today, I'm the big brother, decided!
はい決定！！
Yes, decided!!
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
So annoying! Seriously annoying!
肉まれ口は お口をチャック
Zip your mouth shut with those spiteful words,
鬨の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
raise the battle cry and ring the gong!
次世代エンペラーは この「僕だ」
The next-generation emperor is "me"!
悪ふざけして 悪ノリして
Prank it up, ride the momentum,
ほらほら 煽っていく style で
Come on, go with that teasing style.
一から百 いただきます
Taking everything from one to a hundred,
毎度ありがとうで 君の負け
Thanks as always, you lose!
まさかの引き分け？
Wait, a draw?!
えーっ！？
What?!
金平糖 君が纏う躾直しの季節の匂い
The scent of re-discipline that you wear like konpeito...
下品した纏わず前のわりに脆い其処に触れるの
Touching that surprisingly fragile spot beneath your bold front.
ああ 狂わないで darling だって本当のことだもん身体は大人で格好だけでも中身はガキだよね
Ah, don't go crazy, darling—your body is all grown up and dressed the part, but inside you're just a brat.
暴れないで doggie 私華奢な手だからリードなんて気まぐれでぱっと落としちゃうかも
Don't thrash around, doggie. My hands are delicate, so I might just drop your leash on a whim.
だらし無い 育じ無い 本当キミは救えない
Sloppy, spineless, honestly you're hopeless.
堕落に老けちゃってご愁傷様
Condolences on sinking into depravity.
夢がない 影もない クセに愛が欲しいの
You have no dreams, no shadow, yet you crave love?
なら3回まわっておてから…
Then spin three times and give me your paw...
ルールルルッテトゥルルー
Ru-ru-ru-rut-te-tu-ru-ru...
ルララランネッテルラライ
Ru-ra-ra-ran-net-te-ru-ra-i...
横切ってた大路 ひがみに満ちた人の企み
Crossed paths on the main road, plots filled with jealousy.
この世は物怪だらけね ずっと高校にいて
This world is full of monsters, staying in high school forever...
ひねくれてた応急 生まれぼくサイトの
Twisted first aid, born from my site...
落とせば今日もくせー常套句
If you drop it, today's stinky cliché too.
笑ったってまあえさは気分次第
Smile all you want, but your treats depend on my mood.
ねえ私は知らなかった頃の日々に戻りたい
Hey, I want to go back to the days when I didn't know anything.
ああインターチェップ街のウェーブがストラック
Ah, the waves of the interchange district strike.
もう私を知らなかった頃の君は戻らない
You can't go back to the time when you didn't know me anymore.
だらし無い 育じ無い 本当キミは救えない
Sloppy, spineless, honestly you're hopeless.
どこにもいけないね
You can't go anywhere, can you?
くだらない 果てしない こんな広い世界で 私に落ちていくキミが好き
In this pointless, endless, vast world, I love watching you fall for me.
夢がない 影もない クセに愛が欲しいの
You have no dreams, no shadow, yet you crave love?
なら3回まわっておてから…
Then spin three times and give me your paw...
ルールルルッテトゥルルー
Ru-ru-ru-rut-te-tu-ru-ru...
ルララランネッテルラライ
Ru-ra-ra-ran-net-te-ru-ra-i...
意味わかんねぇ！
I don't get it at all!
どうせ誰も聴いてなんかいないさ
Who cares if no one's listening anyway?
音楽なんてセールスファッション 音鳴らして選手退場ワンナイト
Music's just a sales fashion, players exit in one night
どうせ何も伝えてなんかいないさ
Who cares if nothing's being conveyed?
なんとか撮って撮ってバイ名 アナキって置いてさいでグッドナイト
Snapping pics for clout, bye-bye, get out, good night
どうしたってどう見たって どうしたってしても大渋滞
No matter how you look at it, total gridlock
それがま あっちこっちそっちどっち 卍Zエイジ猿も欲しがる
Here, there, everywhere, Gen-Z, even apes want it
パンチライン欲しいの 意味とかどっちだっていいよ
Wanting punchlines, either meaning is fine
歌詞とかどうでもいいので乗れるのください
Lyrics don't matter, just give me something I can groove to
さあ皆で笑いましょう
Come on, let's all laugh together
芸術より数の大小？
Bigger numbers than art?
ウイルスに酷い代償
A terrible price like a virus
じゃあどうすんの それでいいんだっけ
So what'll you do? Is that really okay?
頭は空回り 死んでいく
Your head spins in circles, dying away
ふざけるな バイバイ バズメロディ
Stop kidding around, bye-bye, buzz melody
疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり ばけんな
Question it all, mostly lies, don't fake it
幻想でも理想でもいい 自分の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい
Daydream or ideal is fine, what happened to what you wanted to sing?
ぶざまでも オーライ 嘘じゃない お金や偽装で満たす前に
Even clumsy is alright, no lie, before filling with money or disguise
負けんな 覚醒せよ鼓動達よ 君の伝えたかったものはどうしたんだい
Don't lose, wake up, heartbeats! What happened to what you wanted to convey?
君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい 意味分かんねえ
What happened to what you wanted to sing? It makes no sense!
くだらないそんな音楽は 現在使われておりません
Such worthless music is currently out of service
ポップシャンのヒットソング聴いて もう一度お確かめください
Listen to pop hits and check again
ああもうハイカラ作家ばかさらくせえわ
Ah, high-collar writers smell so cliché
最期も最期も最期もアイツも 意味分かんねえ
The very end, that guy too, makes no sense!
どうしたってどう見たって どうしたってしても大渋滞
No matter how you look at it, total gridlock
それでもあっちこっちそっちどっち 卍Zエイジ猿も欲しがる
Here, there, everywhere, Gen-Z, even apes want it
パンチライン欲しいの 意味とかどっちだっていいよ
Wanting punchlines, either meaning is fine
歌詞とかどうでもいいので伸びるのください
Lyrics don't matter, just give me something that blows up
さあ皆で払いましょう
Come on, let's all pay up
芸術より安価なんでしょ
Cheaper than art, right?
バイラスに酷い代償 じゃあどうすんの
A terrible price like a virus, so what'll you do?
それでいいんだっけ 頭は空回り
Is that really okay? Your head spins in circles
死んでいく このまじゃ到底終われない
dying away, you can't possibly end like this
ふざけるな バイバイ バズメロディ
Stop kidding around, bye-bye, buzz melody
歌えよ 大げさ 嘘ばかり ばけんな
Sing it out, exaggerated, all lies, don't fake it
幻想でも理想でもいい 君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい
Daydream or ideal is fine, what happened to what you wanted to sing?
このままじゃ到底終われない
You can't possibly end like this
欲しいのはきっとお金じゃない
What you want is surely not money
負けんな 覚醒せよ鼓動達よ
Don't lose, wake up, heartbeats!
君の伝えたかったもんはきっとアンダ ふざけるな
What you wanted to convey is surely under... stop kidding around
ふざけるな バイバイ バズメロディ
Stop kidding around, bye-bye, buzz melody
歌えよ 大概 嘘ばかり ばけんな
Sing it out, mostly lies, don't fake it
幻想でも理想でもいい 君の歌いたかったものはどうしたんだい
Daydream or ideal is fine, what happened to what you wanted to sing?
嘘でも本来 嘘じゃない
Even if a lie, essentially it's no lie
お金や偽装で満たす前に 負けんな 覚醒せよ鼓動達よ
Before filling up with money or disguise, don't lose, wake up, heartbeats!
僕の伝えたかったもんはどうしたんだい 意味分かんねえ
What happened to what I wanted to convey? It makes no sense!
意味分かんねえよ
It makes no sense!
せーの！ すーちゃん！ お誕生日おめでとう！
Ready, set! Su-chan! Happy birthday!
おめでとう！ ありがとう！ おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Thank you! Happy birthday!
なんちゃいになったわけ？
How old did you turn?
20歳バージョン2.0！
20 years old version 2.0!
おめでとう！ おめでとう！ ありがとう！
Congrats! Congrats! Thank you!
ちょっとみんなせっかく来てくれ…
Hey everyone, thanks for coming all the way...
おめでとう！ おめでとう！ おめでとう！ おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
あんた違うでしょ！
You're different!
まだだって、まあ今日的主役ですから水宮は！
Wait, well, Mizumiya is the main character today!
じゃあちょっとみんなに一言言ってね、去ってもらおうかなって。
Then everyone, say a word before you head off.
一人ずつ来なよ、ほら。
Come one by one, come on.
すーにほら、愛をね。
Give Su some love.
一人ずつ来なよ、ほら。ねえ？
Go say a word, come on. Right?
じゃあ誰から、ほら。
Then who's first, come on.
いや、うん。
Umm, yeah.
ママだよ。
I'm mama.
おめでとう！ おめでとう！ おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Congrats! Congrats!
変な人って怖かったでしょ？ おかしくね？
A weird person is scary, right? Isn't that weird?
ママよ。 うん、違うやん。
It's mama. Yeah, that's not it.
ちゃんと、ちゃんと。おめでとう！
Properly, properly. Happy birthday!
はい、これからも利用なお姉ちゃんに頼ってね。
Yep, continue to rely on Riona-neesan.
お姉ちゃんだと思ってるの、本当に？
Do you really think of me as an older sister?
おかしいよ！
That's weird!
ちゃんとほら、愛をね。最後愛をね、すーにね。
Properly, give love at the end, to Su.
いやでも、うちらのスーびびの中やんか。だからせーのって言ったら何に...
Yeah, but inside our Su's fear... So when I say ready, set...
いくよ！
Here we go!
せーの、すいちゃんねる！
Ready, set, Suichan-neru!
くだらない愛の結果で
Born from meaningless love,
僕らは生まれ落ちて
we were brought into this world,
呼吸さえ強いられているけど
forced even to breathe.
綺麗な言葉並べて 醜さに蓋をして
Lining up pretty words, covering up the ugliness,
自分を愛せないままだけど
still unable to love myself.
くだらない嘘をつくたび
Every time I tell a pointless lie,
蒼い色こぼれ落ちた
a blue color spilled out,
ガラスの瞳が綺麗で
glass eyes so beautiful—
君のそのまぶたのように
Like your eyelids,
優しいひとになってさ
become a gentle person,
そんな僕を愛したいんだよ
and I want to love that kind of me.
「わたしの呼吸に終わりがあること」
"That my breathing has an end,"
君の声を見ている
I see your voice.
生まれては消えていくこと、それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away, repeating only that—
「僕らももしまた会えたら」なんて、思っていた
thinking, "If we could meet again someday."
生まれては消えていくだけの蒼白い波に
To the pale waves born only to fade away,
名前をつけることに意味はなかったのか、なんてさ
was there really any meaning in giving them a name?
他愛ない嘘が染みた積み木で遊んでいる
Playing with building blocks stained by harmless lies,
崩れるその日を待っている
waiting for the day they collapse.
澄み切った夜の静寂、君の頬の紅色で
In the crystal-clear silence of night, with the crimson of your cheeks,
もうすぐ桜が咲くのだろう
cherry blossoms will surely bloom soon.
僕らの呼吸に意味がなくても、二人はまた恋をする
Even if our breathing has no meaning, the two of us will fall in love again.
生まれては消えていくこと、それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away, repeating only that—
僕らの呼吸に意味がなくても 二人はまた恋をする
Even if our breathing has no meaning, the two of us will fall in love again.
生まれては消えていくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away, repeating only that—
生まれては消えていくだけの蒼白い波に名前をつけることに意味はなかったのか、なんてさ
Was there any meaning in naming the pale waves that are born only to fade away?
そして君も夜の海に帰っていくんだろう
And you, too, must be returning to the ocean of night.
生まれては消えていくだけの蒼白い波に名前をつけることに囚われている
Trapped in giving a name to the pale waves that are born only to fade away.
ねえ、覚えているかな いつかの春の朝に 桜の樹の下で約束したこと
Hey, do you remember? What we promised under the cherry tree on a spring morning long ago—
想いも君の名前も いつの日か失くしてしまって
memories and your name, losing them someday,
僕もいつか この海とひとつになるんだろう
I, too, will someday become one with this sea.
君のいない冬の空気が僕の頬を刺すその痛みさえ愛していたい
I want to love even the pain of the winter air, without you, piercing my cheeks.
生まれては消えていくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away, repeating only that—
僕らがもしまた会えたらなんて 思っていた
thinking, "If we could meet again someday."
生まれては消えていくだけの蒼白い波に名前をつけることに意味はなかったのかな
Was there really any meaning in naming the pale waves that are born only to fade away?
こうして冬が終わって、青い春が来る
Thus winter ends, and a blue spring arrives.
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) You troubled child,
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) You who are no longer human,
(Be happy!) 怯まず目指せよ
(Be happy!) Aim without fear,
生きているんだし
since we're alive after all.
目を逸した過去も
Even the past you looked away from,
退屈な未来も
and that boring future too—
カウンセリング やれやれ
counseling, good grief.
古今東西
East and West,
ピースピース
peace, peace!
(Unhappy?)
(Unlucky?)
(Be happy!)
(UNDEXD)
(Undead...)
ねぇねぇねぇねぇ 何だかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, why does it feel like we're fighting?
触れられない 触れたくもない
Untouchable, don't even want to touch—
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分 と
my past self, self, self, self...
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
A showdown with a transparent ghost long dead.
幼気で痛い 記憶の奥
Deep inside innocent and painful memories,
残念？ もう居ないのに
regrets? Even though they're gone already—
あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Huh? Is that better? What irony.
透かされているのは 現在の自分？
What's being seen through is my current self?
ナンセンス 消せないレター
Nonsense, an unerasable letter.
Yes! 要はコンプレックス 取り憑かれてるみたい
Yes! In short, a complex, like I'm possessed.
巻き付いたまま まだ離れない
Still wrapped around tightly and won't let go—
在りし日の自分
my former self.
死んじゃいない
You're not dead!
お前と お前の連鎖
You and your chain of connections.
生きていることとは 変変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep changing on and on!
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't just surrender to misery and be satisfied.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
Refusing to try and be happy is cowardly!
この世 この世は 奇怪 奇怪 ファンタジー
This world is a strange, strange fantasy.
次はお鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Who knows what'll appear next—an ogre or a snake?
出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
Meeting and encountering, the story finally begins.
さあ 人か 怪物か
Now, are you human or a monster?
閑話休題 ピース ピース
All joking aside, peace, peace!
Past & Future can't change the past run for the future
何だかどうして 未来になんぞなんの
Why is it that I feel like there's no future at all?
何の希望もない 期待出来ないような気がして
No hope, no expectations, just a lingering feeling.
もう随分 生きている
I've already lived for quite a long time.
既視感とテンプレで食傷 素敵な出来事の気配もない
Sick of déjà vu, not a hint of anything wonderful.
残念 積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Causality of experience, hollowed myths and evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃったなんて
In short, I want thrills, tired of being bored.
整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス 蓋されていくみたい
Guidance falling in line, compliance, getting capped off.
吸い尽くして あれもเหล่านี้どれも同じ味がする
Sucking it all dry, this and that tastes the same.
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
You're not dead! You and your chain of connections.
何時の世も 過去も未来も 現在にあるんだ
In any era, past and future exist in the present.
生きていることを 愚直に果せよ 目指せハッピーエンド
Fulfill your life earnestly, aim for a happy ending!
死んじゃいない お上に言っているんだ
You're not dead! I'm telling this to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であれ
Don't give up on happiness, remain human!
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
If you just get used to suffering and endure it...
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
you're practically dead, a corpse undead.
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) You troubled child,
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) You who are no longer human,
(Be happy!) 怯まず目指せよ 生きているんだろ
(Be happy!) Aim without fear, since you're alive.
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも そう全部全部お前だ
Drowning in misery or finding happiness, it's all up to you.
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピース ピース
East and West, everything, all creation, peace, peace!
Past & Future can't change the past run for the future
人の在る所に何時も憂い事 生き抜けこの化物ばかりの物語
Where people gather, worries are always there. Survive!
ちょこっとヤンチャで ニコッと元気な
A little mischievous, with a cheerful smile—
キラッとスマイル ぷ・れ・あ・で・す！
a sparkling smile, Pleiades!
毎日をもっと楽しくしたいドン
I want to make every day even more fun,
ヤッホー with アドベンチャー
Yahoo with adventure!
ひらひらスカート もちろん着こなせるんだよ
A fluttering skirt, I can wear it well!
だからもっともっと好きになって もいいよ？
So it's okay to love me more and more, right?
一緒に大空に飛び立とう
Let's fly up into the sky together!
光れ starlight どんな輝きの中も
Shine, starlight, even amidst any brilliance,
強いキラメキ キミに届いているかな？
strong sparkle, is it reaching you?
1ミリでも伝われ fight, oh!
Reach you even by 1 millimeter, fight, oh!
チャージ！ チャレンジ！ 全力アクセル
Charge! Challenge! Full throttle accelerator,
がんばるキミへ 一番乗りのスマイルを贈るスバルch
Subaru ch delivering the first-place smile!
everyday night & day みんなで！
Everyday night & day, everyone together!
ブルーな気持ちにズバッと駆けつけ お助けしちゃうヒーロー！
Dashing to your blue feelings, the hero coming to help!
ひらりひらり スカートも ちゃんと気取の知るんだよ
Fluttering skirt, behaving properly too.
だからもっともっと好きになってもいいよ一緒に
So it's okay to love me more together.
大空に飛び立とう
Let's fly up into the open sky!
光れ starlight どんな輝きの中も
Shine, starlight, even amidst any brilliance,
強いキラメキ キミに届いているかな？
strong sparkle, is it reaching you?
1ミリでも伝われ fight, oh!
Reach you even by 1 millimeter, fight, oh!
チャージ！ チャレンジ！ 全力アクセル がんばるキミへ一番乗りのスマイルを
Charge! Challenge! Full throttle to you!
Jumpin’Up Uhh
Jumpin' Up Uhh
Jumpin’Up Uhh Yeh Jumpin’ Jumpin’Up
Jumpin' Up Uhh Yeh Jumpin' Jumpin' Up
鼻歌って お部屋でダンシング
Humming, in my room I'm dancing
汗をかいたら気持ちがいいけど
It feels good to sweat, but
ほら歌って お風呂でコンサート
Look, singing - in my bath a concert
今日もお疲れ様言わせるふ
Thanks for your hard work today too, myself
響く鼓動 響く音を いっぱいいっぱい抱きしめて
Embracing lots and lots of the echoing heartbeats and sounds
踊るティースプーンの かき混ぜるシュガーになりたいの?
Do you want to be the sugar the dancing teaspoon stirs?
Jumpin’Up Uhh 時を忘れるまで
Jumpin' Up Uhh until we forget time
Jumpin’Up Uhh さあ キミの身も
Jumpin' Up Uhh c'mon, you too
Jumpin’Up Uhh 戻ってきた景色
Jumpin' Up Uhh the view's come back
Jumpin’Up Uhh Yeh Jumpin’ Jumpin’Up
Jumpin' Up Uhh Yeh Jumpin' Jumpin' Up
鼻歌って お料理ミュージック
Humming, cooking music
目指すバランス 赤に緑に
Aiming for balance in reds and greens
ほら歌って リビングコンサート
Look, singing - a living room concert
今日もお疲れ様言わせるふ
Thanks for your hard work today too, myself
響く鼓動 響く音を いっぱいいっぱい抱きしめて
Embracing lots and lots of the echoing heartbeats and sounds
踊るティースプーンの かき混ぜるシュガーになりたいの?
Do you want to be the sugar the dancing teaspoon stirs?
Jumpin’Up Uhh 時を忘れるまで
Jumpin' Up Uhh until we forget time
Jumpin’Up Uhh さあ キミの身も
Jumpin' Up Uhh c'mon, you too
Jumpin’Up Uhh 戻ってきた景色
Jumpin' Up Uhh the view's come back
Jumpin’Up Uhh Yeh Jumpin’ Jumpin’Up
Jumpin' Up Uhh Yeh Jumpin' Jumpin' Up
キミに見つけてもらえた それだけでも運命なんだ
Just being found by you is already fate itself.
もっとずっと道は続いてく夢に向かって
The road continues on much further toward our dream.
いっしょに生きてくれるカヌそのペットで走れ
Run with Kobo's pet, who lives together with us!
連れていくよ みんなで
We'll take you along, all of us together!
囁く 恥ずかしいけれど 伝えたい想い
I'm whispering, though I'm embarrassed, feelings I want to convey
今なら言える
I can say them now.
キミのエールが力になるよ いつも元気も分けてくれて
Your cheers give me strength, always sharing your energy with me
頑張っててんだ 笑って過ごせるんだ 本当に
Working hard and smiling through it all, truly.
ありがとうの気持ちを歌え
Sing out the feeling of gratitude
どんな輝きの中も強いきらめき
A strong sparkle within any radiance
キミに届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1ミリでも伝われバイオレット
Even by a millimeter, reach me, violet!
もっとずっと道は続いてく夢に向かって
The road continues on much further toward our dream.
いっしょに生きてくれるカヌそのペットで走れ
Run with Kobo's pet, who lives together with us!
連れていくよ みんなで
We'll take you along, all of us together!
キミとかけるスパル
Running together with you...
すっごい！すっごい！ありがとうございました！カホウヅしまーす！
That was amazing! Thank you very much! We're putting it in a box!
すっごく頑張れー！
Do your very best!
お誕生日おめでとーー！
Happy birthdayyy!
誰かのための痛み？ 僕の願い、やがて 散り散り
Someone's pain for someone else? My wish, eventually scattered
椅子取りゲームみたい それでも、息をしていく しかない
Like a game of musical chairs. Still, I have no choice but to keep breathing.
まだ、聴こえるか？
Can you still hear it?
とっくに頭に詰まった呼吸 関係ない、うるせぇわ
Breath already clogged in my head. Doesn't matter, shut up!
自分だけが聴こえている
Only I can hear it.
安定なんて捨てた もう、すべてを振り切る スピード で
I threw away stability. Now, at a speed that cuts through everything!
その瞬間まで、足掻いて
Struggling until that very moment,
ただ、脳を絞って 今、見えるとこまで
Just squeezing my brain to where I can see now.
この瞬間を飲み干して、また踊って 見たことないもの、見せて
Drink down this moment and dance again. Show me something I've never seen before!
キミの代わりはない もし、誰かが否定しても
No one can replace you, even if someone denies it.
僕の代わりはない 違うことない、僕の目覚まし
No one can replace me. Without a doubt, my awakening!
誰かの祈る手を払った痛み どこから漂う悪意の兆し
The pain of brushing away someone's praying hands. Where do signs of malice drift from?
正しさに息を潜めた怒り それすらも僕に残った光
Anger hiding within righteousness. Even that remained as light within me.
誰かの熱を奪う感覚 逃げる気はとうにないつまり
The sensation of stealing someone's heat. No intention of running away at all.
錯覚を起こした摩擦 まだ、見えてるか？
Friction that caused hallucinations. Can you still see it?
とっくにスポットライトは奪った
I've already taken the spotlight.
この瞬間だけあがいたって意味ないぜ
Struggling in this moment alone is meaningless.
今見えるとこまで 大乱感で生きやって
To where I can see now, live through the chaos!
また踊って 見たことないものを見せて
Dance again and show me something I've never seen before!
今をぶち抜いて もう、ノンストップで
Pierce through the present, already non-stop!
脳擦り切れるまで この瞬間を飲み干して、また踊って 見たことないもの見せて
Until my brain is worn out. Drink down this moment and dance again, show me something I've never seen before!
連れて行かれるように
As if being led away,
踏み出した暗い街へ
into the dark city I stepped into.
tell me what you need アスファルト 背中は黒く染まってた
Tell me what you need, the asphalt's back was dyed black,
wait hold up
悪党? それとも正義? huh?
A villain? Or justice? Huh?
やりがい searching 馬鹿みたい
Searching for a purpose, like an idiot,
目の前の問題はit's too much now 後回しでもまあいいじゃん
The problem right now is it's too much now, putting it off is fine,
人生の意味 結局何? ワンパターンな日々に裏切る声
What's the meaning of life in the end? A voice betraying monotonous days,
あれこれ言ってる間に姿を消し去った君は誰?
While saying all this, who are you who disappeared?
曖昧な世界が変わったあの日
That day when the ambiguous world changed,
ど派手に響かせた声が今も鳴り止まない
The voice that resonated so flashily still doesn't stop ringing.
紅の夜に心奪われて
Captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた
I was reflecting you in this hopeless emotion.
増えてく影を追い 気づけば遠い街で 引き返し元通りになるにはもう遅かった
Chasing growing shadows, before I knew it in a distant town, turning back was too late.
wait hold up now sos逃げ道がないの え、ちょっと待って how is it my fault?
Wait hold up now, SOS, there's no way out. Wait, how is it my fault?
レフト、ライト ステップからのget downに見せかけてclap
Left, right, pretending to get down from the step, clap.
からかっちゃって立場は対等? 助けてやって何その態度
Teasing me, are positions equal? What's that attitude after helping?
不満の中で生まれる依存症 垣間見えてるのは愛
Addiction born from dissatisfaction, what's glimpsed is love.
鬱陶しい世界が変わったあの日
That day when the annoying world changed,
ど派手に響かせた声が今も鳴り止まない
The voice that resonated so flashily still doesn't stop ringing.
紅の夜に心奪われて
Captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた
I was reflecting you in this hopeless emotion.
増えてく影を追い 気づけば遠い街で 引き返し元通りになるにはもう遅かった
Chasing growing shadows, before I knew it in a distant town, turning back was too late.
このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた
I was reflecting you in this hopeless emotion.
はい、はい 腹から声出しして そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまっせ
Yes, yes, shout from your stomach, or you'll get hurt.
勝負負けた歌合戦 枯れそうな地声でまだ歌うのさ
Losing the singing battle, still singing with a raspy voice.
ど派手に響かせた声が今も鳴り止まない
The voice that resonated so flashily still doesn't stop ringing.
紅の夜に心奪われて
Captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた
I was reflecting you in this hopeless emotion.
はい、はい 腹から声出しして そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまっせ
Yes, yes, shout from your stomach, or you'll get hurt.
勝負負けた歌合戦 枯れそうな地声でまだ歌うのさ
Losing the singing battle, still singing with a raspy voice.
紅の夜に心奪われて このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた
Captivated by the crimson night, I was reflecting you in this hopeless emotion.
駆け探って ああごめんねって意味がないね
Searching around, 'Ah, sorry' means nothing,
僕だらけ歩くリズム見失い取り残したい
Walking full of myself, losing the rhythm, wanting to be left behind,
ちゃんと大人になりたい外は晴れて 20でガブルメンソール
Wanting to be a proper adult, outside it's clear, menthol cigarettes at 20,
優しい言葉並べて二人お揃いに甘えて 演じて見せているのは誰の目に見?
Lining up kind words, indulging in matching each other, who's eyes are seeing this acting?
ただ泣きたいように笑っていたんだ
I was smiling just like I wanted to cry,
always on my mind 偽りのディープフェイクか
Always on my mind, a false deepfake,
愛なんてわかんないんだ always on my mind 衣裳まみれのディープフェイク
I don't get love at all, always on my mind, a deepfake covered in clothes.
重ね重ねを浴びします気持ちのない口癖 優しさに吊るさもはき違えて重ね重ねた
Layer upon layer of mindless catchphrases, misunderstanding kindness and hanging it up,
嘘の吐きだけ満たされるマスク まざ20で縛って 心の中散々取り作っている
Masks filled only with breathing lies, bound by 20, putting up a facade deep inside.
心の中散々取り作っている
Putting up a facade deep inside.
うみゃうみゃ！うみゃうみゃ！
Umyau-myau! Umyau-myau!
うにゃうにゃ！うにゃうにゃ！
Unya-unya! Unya-unya!
うみゃうみゃ！うみゃうみゃ！
Umyau-myau! Umyau-myau!
ぐるるん？きゅるるん？
Gururun? Kyururun?
あ～そろそろごはんの時間かな？
Ah~ Is it almost time to eat?
あ、でもでも、やっぱやっぱ
Ah, but still, I really, really
家から一歩も出たくな～い！！
don't want to step a foot outside!
こんな時はそうだ！
I know, at times like this!
飯テロの動画！
Food porn videos!
「説明しよう！極限までお腹を空かせ美味しくいただくのだ！」
"Let me explain! Starve yourself to the limit and eat deliciously!"
めんどいめんどいマジめんどいわ
So troublesome, seriously troublesome,
けっきょくぐだぐだ時間溶けたわ
ended up wasting time slacking off anyway.
ぴろりんぴろりん5回目アラーム
Pirorin pirorin, the 5th alarm,
コンビニいこー
let's go to the convenience store.
わちゃわちゃはちゃめちゃ奇想天外
Chaotic, wild, and out of this world,
ドタバタてんやわんや見逃さない
hustle and bustle, can't miss a thing!
ピンチだってちょちょいのちょいで
Even a pinch is a piece of cake,
てやっ！てやっ！そりゃそりゃ！
Take that! There you go!
万事解決☆
All solved☆
うみゃうみゃうみゃにゃうみゃにゃ
Umyau-myau, umyau-nya, umyau-nya,
おいしくなあれ☆
turn out delicious☆
あれもこれもぜんぶ食べたいのだ（ちょーだいっ！）
I want to eat everything, this and that! (Give it to me!)
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃハピネスライフ
Munching, umyau-myau, happiness life,
食べて寝て遊んでまた食べる（おーいえー！）
eat, sleep, play, and eat again! (Oh yeah!)
ぺこぺこぺこぺこはらぺこじゃー（じゃっ？）
Hungry, hungry, starv'ing! (Huh?)
うみゃうみゃうまくいきません（ぶーっ！ぶーっ！）
Umyau-myau, things aren't going well! (Boo! Boo!)
はぁ…
Haah...
みんな、どうでしたかー？
Everyone, how was it?
いやぁ、ここはですね、あのハウスにね初めて調整したんですけれども
Man, this time, we tried out house music for the very first time here...
あの、2ヶ月で、あの詰め込んで、踊れましたかー？
Uh, crammed it all in two months, were you able to dance along?
いや、めっちゃ頑張ったってコメントが書いてくれるんだろうな。いや、はや。
I bet the comments will say I worked super hard. Man, haha.
でね、あの波に名前をつけること、僕らの国境に終わりがあることって曲では
And you know, in songs like "Naming the Waves" and "Our Borders Coming to an End",
リフトをしたり、あのクルクルね、回って、あれも初めてやりました！踊れてたら嬉しいな！
we did lifts and spinning around—that was my first time doing those too! I'd be so happy if I danced well!
いや、ゲストのね、ハコス先輩、ハジタンとも一緒に元気に踊って
And man, dancing energetically together with our guest Hakos-senpai and Hajitan—
すばる先輩と、あ、憧れのすばる先輩と二人きりでドキドキタイムしちゃったり、
with Subaru-senpai, ah, having a heart-pounding, exclusive moment with my idol Subaru-senpai,
ロボ子先輩とマリンちゃんとは勝って、FGとはかっこよく、いや！ゲストパートもたくさんね、素晴らしいのあったんじゃないでしょうか！
winning against Roboco-senpai and Marine-chan, looking cool with FG... Man, weren't there so many amazing guest parts too!
ゲストパートもたくさんね、素晴らしいのがあったんじゃないでしょうか！
There were so many wonderful guest parts, weren't there!
ということで、皆さん、何か忘れてませんか？
So everyone, is there something you're forgetting?
ね、皆さん、そろそろね、の休憩タイムもね、もうそろそろ終わらないといけない。
Hey everyone, our break time is almost coming to an end.
よし、立つか！
Alright, time to get up!
はい、ということで、なんとですね、こんな感じで言うのもなんですが、新曲が出まーす！いえーい！初のおしゃれ曲！
Yes! So, believe it or not, a new song is coming out! Yay! My very first stylish song!
ふふふふっ、やばい、体が疲れた。よしよし。はい、ということで、
Haha, oh man, my body is tired. Alright. So,
作詞作曲、編曲はサトダユーリさんに作ってもらいました！
the lyrics, composition, and arrangement were made by Satoda Yuri-san!
ありがとう！どんどんばふぁふふ、どんどんばふぁふふ～！
Thank you! Donton-bafafuu, donton-bafafuu~!
はい、このあとすぐMV公開がね、この配信が終わったあとあるのですが、
Right after this stream ends, the MV will premiere,
リダレクトで飛びます。そしてデジタルリリースは今日の0時からなので、
so you'll be redirected there. And since the digital release starts tonight at midnight,
たくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you listen to it a lot!
じゃあ、ちょっと早速なんですけど、その新曲をお披露目しちゃおうかな。
So, without further ado, I'd like to premiere that new song right now.
いや、どんな楽曲なんだろう！気になるな！どんな楽曲なんだろ、いきます！
Man, I wonder what kind of song it is! I'm so curious! What kind of song is it, here we go!
うみゃうみゃ！うみゃうみゃ！
Umyau-myau! Umyau-myau!
うにゃうにゃ！うにゃうにゃ！
Unya-unya! Unya-unya!
うみゃうみゃ！うみゃうみゃ！
Umyau-myau! Umyau-myau!
ぐるるん？きゅるるん？
Gururun? Kyururun?
ぐるるんきゅるるん あ～そろそろごはんの時間かな？
Gururun, kyururun... Ah~ Is it almost time to eat?
あ、でもでも、やっぱやっぱ 家から一歩も出たくな～い！
Ah, but still, I really, really don't want to step a foot outside!
こんな時はそうだ！飯テロの動画！
I know, at times like this! Food porn videos!
めんどいめんどいマジめんどいわ
So troublesome, seriously troublesome,
けっきょくぐだぐだ時間溶けたわ
ended up wasting time slacking off anyway.
ぴろりんぴろりん5回目アラーム
Pirorin pirorin, the 5th alarm,
コンビニいこー
let's go to the convenience store.
わちゃわちゃはちゃめちゃ奇想天外
Chaotic, wild, and out of this world,
ドタバタてんやわんや見逃さない
hustle and bustle, can't miss a thing!
ピンチだってちょちょいのちょいで
Even a pinch is a piece of cake,
てやっ！てやっ！そりゃそりゃ！万事解決☆
Take that! There you go! All solved☆
うみゃうみゃうみゃにゃうみゃにゃ
Umyau-myau, umyau-nya, umyau-nya,
おいしくなあれ☆
turn out delicious☆
あれもこれもぜんぶ食べたいのだ（ちょーだいっ！）
I want to eat everything, this and that! (Give it to me!)
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃハピネスライフ
Munching, umyau-myau, happiness life,
食べて寝て遊んでまた食べる
eat, sleep, play, and eat again!
ぺこぺこぺこぺこはらぺこじゃー（じゃっ？）
Hungry, hungry, starv'ing! (Huh?)
うみゃうみゃうまくいきません（ぶーっ！ぶーっ！）
Umyau-myau, things aren't going well! (Boo! Boo!)
うみゃうみゃ！うみゃうみゃ！うにゃうにゃ！
Umyau-myau! Umyau-myau! Unya-unya!
あ〜い天気〜あの雲ソフトクリームみたい！
Ah, what nice weather~ like that cloud soft serve!
あ、あっち側はわたし！
Ah, that side is me!
雲ってふわふわで美味しそう…
Clouds are fluffy and look delicious...
人生で1回は食べてみたいよねぇ
I'd love to eat one at least once in my life~
じゃない！！
No it's not!!
しんどいしんどいマジしんどいわ
Tough, tough, seriously tough,
現実逃避何度もしちゃうわ
I escape reality over and over.
妄想 空想 頭が暴走
Delusion, fantasy, my head runs wild.
カツオ食べたーい！！！
I want to eat bonito!!!
だらだらぐだら怠惰全開
Lazing around, laziness at full throttle,
ネガティブ思考もご愛敬です！
even negative thinking is charming!
世界だってぽっぽいのぽいで
Even the world is all easy-peasy,
えいやっ えいやっ とりゃっ とりゃっ
Ei-ya! Ei-ya! Tori-ya! Tori-ya!
ねじ伏せっちゃおうぞ☆
Let's beat it down☆
うみゃうみゃうみゃうみゃうにゃうにゃ
Umya umya umya umya unya unya
お腹空いたらどうせとなりの晩ごはん
When hungry, after all, next door's dinner
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃ幸せタイム
Munch munch, umya umya, happy time,
満腹食欲で生きてます
living with full appetite.
だからどうかお願いこのおなかを満たして神様
So please, I beg you, fill this belly, God!
たべたーい 寝てたーい
I want to eat, I want to sleep,
むずかしいことは何も考えたくない
I don't want to think about difficult things at all.
おとと、みんなでお菓子パーティしたーい！！
Oh, and I want us all to have a snack party!!
うみゃうみゃうみゃうみゃおいしくなれ
Umya umya umya umya, become delicious,
あれもこれも全部食べたいな
I want to eat this and that and everything!
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃハピネスライフ
Munch munch, umya umya, happiness life,
食べて寝て遊んでまた食べ
eating, sleeping, playing, eating again,
ぺこぺこぺこぺこ腹ぺこじゃ
Starving, starving, starving, so hungry!
うみゃうみゃうみゃうまくいきません
Umya umya umya, things don't go well,
ひとまずごはんをおなかいっぱい食べさせて
so first let me eat my fill of rice!
まだ足りないもっともっと食べさせて
Not enough yet, let me eat more and more!
新曲どうだった？ 可愛かったでしょ？
How was the new song? Wasn't it cute?
「かわいい」っていうコメントがたくさん見えます。ありがとね！かわいいかわいいありがと、知ってる知ってる。
I see lots of "cute" comments. Thank you! Cute, cute, thanks, I know, I know.
ということでね、新曲のタイトルは「うみゃうにゃはっぴーらいふ」でしたーー！
So, the title of the new song was "Umya Unya Happy Life"~~!
今回はちょっと可愛い感じにしたので、次はなんかかっこいい感じにしたいなみたいな、ま、何も決まってないですけどね。
This time I went for a cute vibe, so next time I want something cool... well, nothing's decided yet though.
ということで、新曲が終わったからって帰ろうとしてない？ねえ、なんか忘れてるよなみんな。と、いうことで、グッズーー！
So, since the new song is over, aren't you trying to head home? Hey, you guys are forgetting something, right? And so, merchandise~~!
水宮諏訪誕生日記念2026のグッズをさっそく1つずつ見ていこー！
Let's check out the goods for Mizumiya Su's 2026 Birthday Commemoration one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
オーロラアクリルパネル！公式イラストレーターのぶくるて先生に描いていただきました！ありがとママ〜！
Aurora acrylic panel! Drawn by our official illustrator, Bukurote-sensei! Thank you, Mama~!
ふわふわのね、お部屋でお茶会みたいなね、可愛い感じになっております！もうママが天才すぎるのでぜひ買ってください！
It has a cute vibe like having a tea party in a fluffy room! Mama is such a genius, so please definitely buy it!
2つ目は、こちら！
Second is this!
ハート型缶バッジ！ハートハートハート！
Heart-shaped tin badge! Heart, heart, heart!
こちらはね、もう可愛いお顔がドアップになってで、すうたぶんハート型の缶バッジは初めてなんじゃないかなと思っているので、ぜひこちらも買ってみてください！
This one features a close-up of her cute face, and I think it's Su's very first heart-shaped tin badge, so please definitely buy this one too!
3つ目が、こちら！
The third one is this!
おくるみすうぬいぐるみ！こちらもね、すうちゃんがおくるみに入っています！
Swaddle Su plushie! In this one too, Su-chan is wrapped in a swaddle!
まあなんかすうをね、結構おくるみに入れてくれてる方も見たりとかしたのて、もしよかったらみんなこういうのを待っていたんじゃないかなと思って作りました！衣装はね、キビズの衣装で、外小さめのぬいぐるみを作ってみました！
Well, I've seen quite a few people putting Su in swaddles, so I thought maybe everyone was waiting for something like this and made it! The outfit is the Kibiz outfit, and I tried making a smaller plushie!
4つ目は、こちら！
The fourth one is this!
れきお一推しショルダーバッグ！こちらにですね、さっきのハート型のね、缶バッジとかおくるみぬいぐるみが入れるように入るようになってます！はい、天才天才天才！
Rekio Oioshi shoulder bag! This is designed so you can put the heart-shaped tin badge and swaddle plushie inside! Yes, genius, genius, genius!
ということで、こちらも一緒にぜひれきおのね、推し活のバッグに入れて、すうをね、あの可愛く持ってくださーい！よろしくね！他の推しもぜひ入れてみてね！
So, please put this together with Rekio's oshi-katsu bag and carry Su around cutely! Thank you! Try putting your other oshis in too!
5つ目が、こちら！
The fifth one is this!
ボイス！タイトルは「すうとのお茶会」！こちらはね、おうちで優雅な優雅な優雅なアフタヌーンティを楽しむすうと一緒にね、いっぱい楽しんじゃおボイスとなっております！
Voice pack! Titled "Tea Party with Su"! This voice pack is all about enjoying a luxurious, elegant afternoon tea at home together with Su, having lots of fun!
最後にフルセット！直筆サイン入りオリジナルカードと特典ASMRボイスがついてきまーす！
Lastly, the full set! Comes with a hand-signed original card and bonus ASMR voice~!
おうちに お呼ばれしちゃったみんながね、ちょっと距離つかめでね、
Everyone invited to my house... keeping a bit of distance,
ASMRボイスが、なんかこんな感じ、まあちょっとなんか適当なんですけど、まあそんな感じのボイスになっております！
the ASMR voice is... well, sort of like this, it's a bit casual, but it's turned into that kind of voice!
こちら、数量限定じゃない ので、焦らずに みんなゆっくりで大丈夫です。
This isn't quantity-limited, so don't panic, everyone can take their time, it's fine.
グッズは、22時、22時10分 から販売開始です。
Goods go on sale starting at 22:00, no, 22:10.
直筆のサインとかもね、全部、なにもかも 数量限定じゃないので、あの、すーちゃんのサインも、あの、ついてきますのでね、フルセットを買ったら、
Autographs and everything else are not limited in quantity either, so Su-chan's autograph will also come with it if you buy the full set,
皆さんよろしくお願いします！是非、買ってね！いっぱいいっぱい買ってね！
so everyone please look forward to it! Please buy it! Buy lots and lots!
はい、ということで、以上、ミニミアによるグッズ紹介でした！
Yes, with that, that was Mini-Mia's merchandise introduction!
はい、ということで、ミニミアありがとうー！
Yes, with that, thank you, Mini-Mia!
なんか結構ミスってたかな。まあ、ミニミアだからね、まあすーちゃんじゃないから、まあ、仕方ないか。
I feel like I made quite a few mistakes. Well, it's Mini-Mia, not Su-chan, so I guess it can't be helped.
ということで、誕生日の3Dライブはどうだったでしょうか？
So, how was the birthday 3D live?
憧れのフルライブに入ってからみんなにいっぱい応援してもらってここまで来れました。
Ever since entering my dream full live, with everyone cheering me on so much, I've made it this far.
みんなに 少しでもね、かっこよかったとか、すーちゃんのこと応援しててよかったって思ってもらえてるととっても嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if everyone thought even a little bit that I looked cool or that they're glad they cheered for Su-chan.
MVはこのあとすぐ 公開でリダイレクトで飛ぶのでチャンネルはそのままでよろしくお願いします！
The MV will premiere right after this and redirect you there, so please keep your channel tuned in!
ということで、みんな、これからもよろしくね！ありがとう！
So everyone, thank you for your continued support! Thank you!
じゃあ、バイバイ！またねーー！
Well then, bye-bye! See you later!
ずりっすへ ずっと見守ってて、応援してくれてありがとう！
To Zuri-su: Thank you for always watching over and supporting me!
そのすーちゃんのかんにんしてをみせるかも…
I might show you Su-chan losing patience...
わかんないけどじぶんのきもちになるよ♪
I'm not sure, but it becomes my true feeling♪
これからもコンサートもたのしんでおしえてね。
Please keep enjoying concerts and telling me about them.
すずがあんしんするのはずりっすのおかげ!!
Suzu can feel at ease all thanks to Zuri-su!!